<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>deekap.com - Personal</title><link href="https://deekap.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://deekap.com/feeds/personal.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://deekap.com/</id><updated>2024-10-22T00:00:00+11:00</updated><entry><title>Beyond Code</title><link href="https://deekap.com/2024/10/22/beyond-code/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-10-22T00:00:00+11:00</published><updated>2024-10-22T00:00:00+11:00</updated><author><name>Deepak</name></author><id>tag:deekap.com,2024-10-22:/2024/10/22/beyond-code/</id><summary type="html"></summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;One of the reasons I started this blog back in 2003 was to use it as a marketing tool for myself. Personal branding had started to become a thing and blogging scene was about to take off big time. I was fortunate enough to grab on to it and together with other community activities, it worked out well for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Software is still my passion but there are also other interests I pursue. Reading, Cooking, Finance, photography are some of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lately I have been pondering the question of merging my tech and non-tech writings in one place. I am much more than a programmer and those aspects do not get any space online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A question comes to mind: Why bother writing about them at all? Why not just enjoy non-tech adventures in obscurity? Does the world need to know about them?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all, I'm confident that this blog is read only by 2 people. One of them is me and the other I have yet to know about. Secondly, and more importantly &lt;mark&gt;this website exists only to serve me&lt;/mark&gt; If anyone else finds anything useful here then it it incidental and not intentional. It is after all a log of my life which will be of no interest to anyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that thought, I decided to make it more complete by writing about the books I have read, the journeys I have been on (there are not too many), photos I have clicked and a lot more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, tinkering with this website gives me the joy similar to working in the garage with tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here it is to a more authentic place which is both about and beyond code. Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Personal"></category></entry><entry><title>Few thoughts on Blogging</title><link href="https://deekap.com/2022/05/01/few-thoughts-on-blogging/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-05-01T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2022-05-01T00:00:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Deepak</name></author><id>tag:deekap.com,2022-05-01:/2022/05/01/few-thoughts-on-blogging/</id><summary type="html"></summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;According to the &lt;a href="https://online.ndm.edu/news/communication/history-of-blogging/"&gt;History of Blogging&lt;/a&gt;, the first blog was created in 1994. The term weblog which eventually became &lt;a href="/"&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; was coined in 1997.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me blogging started around 2003 when Wordpress was launched. This was also the time when I was heavily invested in Microsoft ecosystem. After spending many years working with ASP and VB, I found .NET to be a relief. During this time I also got involved with the local &lt;a href="https://www.ssw.com.au/ssw/NETUG/SSWUpdate/_2006_02__Do%20you%20understand%20the%20value%20of%20consistency_.htm"&gt;Microsoft community&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I created a website which I don't remember and wrote content which is not relevant or useful to either me or anyone else (I think). This went on for few years and I finally hosted my blog on my own domain called &lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20100602053942/http://www.onedotnetway.com/page/2/"&gt;OneDotNetWay.com&lt;/a&gt;. I no longer own that domain. At that time, I thought that my site looked kinda cool. Yes, this is an opinion :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="onedotnetway.com" src="/images/posts/onedotnetway.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things were looking good and my blog was getting popular. The traffic was growing and other popular sites were linking to my content. It was nowhere near some of the &lt;a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/"&gt;top technical blogs&lt;/a&gt; of that time, but still I was enjoying the attention and benefits I was getting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that only-interesting-to-me history, it is time to reflect on the good and bad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Good&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blogging as a anybody (programmer, investor, artist, cook, social worker) has many benefits. It has almost no barriers to entry but in it lies the power of Internet. One has access to limitless reach with a basic tool such as a laptop. There is a potential to form relations by expressing yourself through this medium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have experienced an upward trajectory in my career because of the content I produced. People have reached out to me because of a blog post I wrote which eventually resulted in a consulting gig.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another big benefit is that writing is an excellent way to sharpen your skills. When you write something which other people will read, you tend to be a bit more careful about your words and the message you are delivering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has also helped me identify my weak areas and there are plenty. There have been times when my assumptions around what I know were knocked to the ground as soon as I started writing about it. This motivated me to go deep into a topic which increased my knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The blog also served as my own repository of knowledge which I could turn to in times of need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Bad&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't see anything bad about blogging or having an online presence. The only negative I can see is that I abandoned a good thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What now?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been thinking of getting back into it for sometime and I have made some trial attempts. I have been collecting notes in Notion and I feel that I have started enjoying the process of writing once again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the things I'm doing differently is that this blog has one and only purpose i.e. to serve me. If anyone else gets any benefit out of this, it is purely incidental.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's see how it goes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After all&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is not a race&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Namaste.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Personal"></category><category term="Blogging"></category></entry></feed>